<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">JAMA Netw Open</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">JAMA Netw Open</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">3211</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">jamasd</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-id">101729235</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>JAMA Network Open</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2574-3805</issn><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-is-collection-domain</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-collection-title</meta-name><meta-value>JAMA Network</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11780474</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC11780474.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">11780474</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">11780474</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">39878978</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2024.57079</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">zoi241597</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="category" specific-use="electronic"><subject>Research</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Original Investigation</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="online-only"><subject>Online Only</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="subject-area"><subject>Psychiatry</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Sensitivity to Environmental Stress and Adversity and Lung Cancer</article-title><alt-title alt-title-type="headline">Sensitivity to Environmental Stress and Adversity and Lung Cancer</alt-title><alt-title alt-title-type="running-head">Sensitivity to Environmental Stress and Adversity and Lung Cancer</alt-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names initials="Y">Yingxi</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><degrees>PhD</degrees><xref rid="zoi241597aff1" ref-type="aff">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lan</surname><given-names initials="Q">Qing</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><degrees>PhD</degrees><xref rid="zoi241597aff1" ref-type="aff">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Yu</surname><given-names initials="J">Jing</given-names></name><degrees>PhD</degrees><xref rid="zoi241597aff2" ref-type="aff">
<sup>2</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Godbole</surname><given-names initials="D">Devika</given-names></name><degrees>MS</degrees><xref rid="zoi241597aff1" ref-type="aff">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Byun</surname><given-names initials="J">Jinyoung</given-names></name><degrees>PhD</degrees><xref rid="zoi241597aff3" ref-type="aff">
<sup>3</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Amos</surname><given-names initials="CI">Christopher I.</given-names></name><degrees>PhD</degrees><xref rid="zoi241597aff3" ref-type="aff">
<sup>3</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names initials="H">Haoyu</given-names></name><degrees>PhD</degrees><xref rid="zoi241597aff1" ref-type="aff">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="zoi241597aff1"><label>1</label>Division of Cancer Epidemiology and Genetics, National Cancer Institute, National Institutes of Health, Rockville, Maryland</aff><aff id="zoi241597aff2"><label>2</label>Division of Population Health Research, Eunice Kennedy Shriver, National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland</aff><aff id="zoi241597aff3"><label>3</label>Institute for Clinical and Translational Research, Department of Medicine, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, Texas</aff><author-notes><title>Article Information</title><p><bold>Accepted for Publication:</bold> November 22, 2024.</p><p content-type="published-online"><bold>Published:</bold> January 29, 2025. doi:<uri content-type="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2024.57079</uri></p><p content-type="open-access-note"><bold>Open Access:</bold> This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://jamanetwork.com/pages/cc-by-license-permissions" ext-link-type="uri">CC-BY License</ext-link>. © 2025 Chen Y et al. <italic toggle="yes">JAMA Network Open</italic>.</p><corresp id="zoi241597cor1"><bold>Corresponding Author:</bold> Yingxi Chen, MD, PhD, National Cancer Institute, National Institutes of Health, 9609 Medical Center Dr, Rockville, MD 20850 (<email xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="yingxi.chen@nih.gov">yingxi.chen@nih.gov</email>).</corresp><p content-type="author-contributions"><bold>Author Contributions:</bold> Drs Chen and Zhang had full access to all of the data in the study and take responsibility for the integrity of the data and the accuracy of the data analysis.</p><p><italic toggle="yes">Concept and design:</italic> Chen, Yu, Zhang.</p><p><italic toggle="yes">Acquisition, analysis, or interpretation of data:</italic> Chen, Lan, Godbole, Byun, Amos.</p><p><italic toggle="yes">Drafting of the manuscript:</italic> Chen, Amos, Zhang.</p><p><italic toggle="yes">Critical review of the manuscript for important intellectual content:</italic> Chen, Lan, Yu, Godbole, Byun, Amos.</p><p><italic toggle="yes">Statistical analysis:</italic> Chen, Lan, Godbole.</p><p><italic toggle="yes">Obtained funding:</italic> Chen, Amos.</p><p><italic toggle="yes">Administrative, technical, or material support:</italic> Chen, Byun, Amos.</p><p><italic toggle="yes">Supervision:</italic> Chen, Zhang.</p><p content-type="COI-statement"><bold>Conflict of Interest Disclosures:</bold> Dr Amos reported receiving grants from the National Cancer Institute during the conduct of the study and grants from National Cancer Institute outside the submitted work. No other disclosures were reported.</p><p content-type="funding-statement"><bold>Funding/Support:</bold> This study was funded by the National Cancer Institute Intramural Research Program.</p><p><bold>Role of the Funder/Sponsor:</bold> The funders had no role in the design and conduct of the study; collection, management, analysis, and interpretation of the data; preparation, review, or approval of the manuscript; and decision to submit the manuscript for publication.</p><p content-type="data-sharing-statement"><bold>Data Sharing Statement:</bold> See <xref rid="note-ZOI241597-1-s" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplement 2</xref>.</p></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub" iso-8601-date="2025-01-29T10:00"><day>29</day><month>1</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><month>1</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><volume>8</volume><issue>1</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">480840</issue-id><elocation-id>e2457079</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>30</day><month>8</month><year>2024</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>22</day><month>11</month><year>2024</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>29</day><month>01</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>31</day><month>01</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2026-06-07 02:25:21.120"><day>07</day><month>06</month><year>2026</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright 2025 Chen Y et al. <italic toggle="yes">JAMA Network Open</italic>.</copyright-statement><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the CC-BY License.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="jamanetwopen-e2457079.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pdf-version" xlink:href="jamanetwopen-e2457079.pdf">jamanetwopen-e2457079.pdf</self-uri><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="silverchair" xlink:href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2024.57079"/><abstract abstract-type="key-points"><title>Key Points</title><sec id="ab-zoi241597-1"><title>Question</title><p>Is genetically estimated sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity associated with the risk of lung cancer?</p></sec><sec id="ab-zoi241597-2"><title>Findings</title><p>In this genetic association study of 351 827 individuals from UK Biobank and a cross-ancestry genome-wide analysis of 61 047 lung cancer cases and 947 237 controls from the International Lung Cancer Consortium, sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity was significantly associated with a 49% increased risk of lung cancer in individuals of European ancestry and a 45% increased risk in the cross-ancestry analysis.</p></sec><sec id="ab-zoi241597-3"><title>Meaning</title><p>These findings suggest support for a potential causal link between sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity and the risk of lung cancer.</p></sec></abstract><abstract abstract-type="teaser" specific-use="electronic"><p>This genetic association study examines genetically estimated sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity among individuals with and without lung cancer.</p></abstract><abstract><sec id="ab-zoi241597-4"><title>Importance</title><p>Sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity may influence lung cancer risk, highlighting a critical link between psychosocial factors and cancer etiology.</p></sec><sec id="ab-zoi241597-5"><title>Objective</title><p>To evaluate whether genetically estimated sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity is associated with lung cancer risk.</p></sec><sec id="ab-zoi241597-6"><title>Design, Setting, and Participants</title><p>Data were obtained from a genome-wide association study identifying 37 independent genetic variants strongly associated with sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity and a cross-ancestry genome-wide meta-analysis from the International Lung Cancer Consortium. Data were extracted between October 2023 and January 2024 and analyzed between February 2024 and June 2024.</p></sec><sec id="ab-zoi241597-7"><title>Exposures</title><p>Genetically estimated sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity.</p></sec><sec id="ab-zoi241597-8"><title>Main Outcomes and Measures</title><p>The main outcome was lung cancer risk, and odds ratios and 95% CIs were used to assess the association between sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity with lung cancer risk. This genetic association study used a 2-sample Mendelian randomization (MR) to estimate the association between genetically estimated sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity and lung cancer risk across different histologic types.</p></sec><sec id="ab-zoi241597-9"><title>Results</title><p>Using data from 351 827 individuals from the UK Biobank and a cross-ancestry genome-wide analysis of 61 047 lung cancer cases and 947 237 controls from the International Lung Cancer Consortium, sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity was significantly associated with an increased risk of lung cancer among individuals of European ancestry (OR, 1.49; 95% CI, 1.13-1.98; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .005) and in the cross-ancestry analysis (OR, 1.45; 95% CI, 1.13-1.85; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .004). There were heterogeneities in the observed associations across histologic subtypes among different population ancestries. Among individuals of European ancestry, a significant association was noted among squamous cell carcinoma (OR, 1.69; 95% CI, 1.06-2.70; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .03). Among individuals of East Asian ancestry, an increased risk was observed for adenocarcinoma (OR, 2.04; 95% CI, 1.00-4.18; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .05). Associations were not observed across any of the 3 histologic subtypes among individuals of African ancestry.</p></sec><sec id="ab-zoi241597-10"><title>Conclusions and Relevance</title><p>In this genetic association study, sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity was associated with lung cancer risk. These results underscore the necessity for further research into the nuanced association between psychosocial stress and cancer risk, with a particular focus on diverse populations.</p></sec></abstract><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="H1-1-ZOI241597"><title>Introduction</title><p>Sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity is a highly heritable personality trait with significant effects on physical and mental health across the lifespan.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> Stress, arising from adverse external or internal forces, triggers the release of stress hormones, such as epinephrine and norepinephrine, affecting metabolism and other vital physiological functions.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref></sup> Environmental adversity can induce epigenetic changes, such as DNA methylation, altering the functioning of genes involved in stress responses, immune function, and inflammation.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref></sup> Moreover, chronic exposure to stress and adversity can lead to low-grade systemic inflammation, promoting tissue damage and dysregulating immune function.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref></sup> Consequently, prolonged exposure to stress and environmental adversity can lead to various health conditions, potentially increasing cancer risk, including lung cancer.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref></sup></p><p>In 2022, global lung cancer incidence varied widely with the highest rates observed in Central and Eastern Europe and Eastern Asia and the lowest in sub-Saharan Africa (except South Africa).<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref></sup> Gender and regional differences are notable, with men experiencing the highest lung cancer incidence rates in Central and Eastern Europe, Southern Europe, Western Asia, and Melanesia (56 to 68 men per 100 000), while women have the highest rates in the United States, Canada, China, the Netherlands, and Denmark (30 to 35 women per 100 000).<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref></sup> Historically, smoking patterns have driven these trends, with men in high-income countries adopting and quitting smoking earlier than women. Consequently, lung cancer death rates among men have declined since the late 1980s in regions such as North America, Northern and Western Europe, and Australia, while women death rates have plateaued or continue to rise due to delayed reductions in smoking prevalence. Other risk factors, such as environmental hazards and genetic susceptibility, also play important roles.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,<xref rid="zoi241597r8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,<xref rid="zoi241597r9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref></sup> While stress has been related to various adverse health outcomes, its association with lung cancer remains poorly understood. A meta-analysis of 16 observational studies reported a significant association between stress and lung cancer incidence.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref></sup> Despite this, the causal relationship remains uncertain, and it is unclear whether this association holds consistent across different histologic types of lung cancer.</p><p>In scenarios where randomized trials are not feasible, Mendelian randomization (MR) analysis offers a compelling alternative by using human genetic data.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref></sup> MR leverages naturally occurring genetic variants as unbiased proxies for exposures to make potential causal inference. Our study employs a 2-sample MR analysis, using single nucleotide variants (SNVs) as genetic instruments. Leveraging data from the largest multiancestry genome-wide association studies (GWAS) of lung cancer from the International Lung Cancer Consortium (ILCCO)<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref></sup> and a GWAS published by Nagel et al<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> on sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity using the UK Biobank, we aim to examine the causal association of sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity in relation to lung cancer risk. This analysis may provide novel insights to enhance our understanding of the etiology and biology of psychosocial stress in relation to lung cancer risk.</p></sec><sec id="H1-2-ZOI241597"><title>Methods</title><p>This study follows the Strengthening the Reporting of Genetic Association Studies (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.equator-network.org/reporting-guidelines/strobe-strega/" ext-link-type="uri">STREGA</ext-link>) reporting guideline. Cohorts participating in the UK Biobank and the GWAS Lung Cancer Consortium received ethics approval from local institutional review boards and informed consent from all participants.</p><sec id="H2-1-ZOI241597"><title>Data Acquisition</title><p>We obtained summary-level statistic data for genetic instruments from the GWAS of sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity using data collected from individuals of European descent from the UK Biobank.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> Sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity was measured through questions assessing emotional reactivity, such as, “Are your feelings easily hurt?” “Do you worry too long after an embarrassing experience?” and “Are you often troubled by feelings of guilt?” These items, which were grouped based on their shared theme, define sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity as a distinct genetic cluster.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> We obtained the summary-level statistic data for lung cancer risk, both overall and across histologic subtypes, from a comprehensive multiancestry GWAS from 12 studies of diverse ancestry populations from the ILCCO published by Byun et al.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref></sup> The cohort predominantly consisted of individuals of European ancestry (74%), followed by those of East Asian (18%) and African ancestry (8%).<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref></sup> The study specifically focused on histological subtypes of lung cancer, including small cell lung cancer, squamous cell carcinoma, and lung adenocarcinoma.</p><p>This study analyzed data from individuals of African ancestry, East Asian ancestry, and European ancestry. These populations were included to investigate potential differences in the association between sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity, and lung cancer risk across diverse populations. Such inclusion allows for a comprehensive assessment of factors that may vary by ancestry and influence susceptibility to lung cancer. Additionally, stratifying by ancestry helps ensure that findings are more generalizable and that disparities or unique patterns in lung cancer risk among different populations are appropriately captured and addressed.</p></sec><sec id="H2-2-ZOI241597"><title>Instrumental Variables and Genetic Proxies for Exposure</title><p>For the current study, we selected 4463 genome-wide significant SNVs (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 5 × 10<sup>−8</sup>) associated with sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity that were also present in the lung cancer outcome GWAS dataset.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="zoi241597r11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref></sup> To maintain independence among genetic proxies, we then performed linkage disequilibrium (LD) clumping with a threshold of <italic toggle="yes">r<sup>2</sup></italic> = 0.01, within a 1000 kb window using genotype data from European individuals of the 1000 Genomes Project (Phase 3) as reference panel,<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref></sup> using PLINK version 1.9.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref></sup> This process yielded 38 SNVs. Subsequently, 1 SNV (rs7938812), known to be associated with smoking behavior,<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref></sup> was excluded to prevent potential confounding. The remaining 37 SNVs do not have known associations with risk or carcinogenic factors associated with lung cancer, and thus, were included in the MR analysis (<xref rid="zoi241597t1" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref> and eTable 1 in <xref rid="note-ZOI241597-1-s" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplement 1</xref>).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="zoi241597t1" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1. </label><caption><title>Candidate Genetic Instruments of Sensitivity to Environmental Stress and Adversity</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><col width="14.17%" span="1"/><col width="20.32%" span="1"/><col width="19.59%" span="1"/><col width="22.09%" span="1"/><col width="23.83%" span="1"/><thead><tr><th rowspan="2" valign="top" align="left" scope="col" colspan="1">Selection criteria</th><th colspan="4" valign="top" align="left" scope="colgroup" rowspan="1">Participants and genetic instruments, No.</th></tr><tr><th valign="top" colspan="1" align="left" scope="colgroup" rowspan="1">Ancestry of participants</th><th valign="top" align="left" scope="col" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Candidate genetic instruments</th><th valign="top" align="left" scope="col" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Genetic instruments after LD clumping</th><th valign="top" align="left" scope="col" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Final genetic instruments used in the analysis</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td valign="top" align="left" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 5 × 10<sup>−8</sup></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">European, UK Biobank, 351 827</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4463</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">38</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">37</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>Abbreviation: LD, linkage disequilibrium.</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec><sec id="H2-3-ZOI241597"><title>Statistical Analysis</title><p>We conducted a 2-sample MR analysis primarily using the robust adjusted profile score (MR-RAPS) method to estimate the odds ratio (OR) and 95% CI for the association between sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity with lung cancer risk, both overall and across histologic subtypes.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup> We conducted sensitivity analysis using 2 additional MR methods, debiased inverse-variance weighted (dIVW) and MR median, to evaluate robustness of the results. To assess if the association differed by population ancestry and to provide cross-ancestry estimates, we performed meta-analysis using random effects model. All statistical analyses were performed in R version 4.3.1 (R Project for Statistical Computing) with the packages MendelianRandomization, mr.raps, and meta. A 2-tailed <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; .05 was considered statistically significant. Summary statistics are available at the following links: sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref></sup> and lung cancer.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref></sup></p></sec></sec><sec id="H1-3-ZOI241597"><title>Results</title><sec id="H2-4-ZOI241597"><title>Association With Overall Lung Cancer Risk</title><p>In this genetic association study of 351 827 individuals from the UK Biobank and a cross-ancestry genome-wide analysis of 61 047 lung cancer cases and 947 237 controls from the International Lung Cancer Consortium, sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity was significantly associated with an increased risk of lung cancer in individuals of European ancestry (OR, 1.49; 95% CI, 1.13-1.98; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .005) and in the cross-ancestry analysis (OR, 1.45; 95% CI, 1.13-1.85; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .004) (<xref rid="zoi241597t2" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref> and <xref rid="zoi241597f1" ref-type="fig">Figure</xref>). Nonetheless, for individuals of African and East Asian ancestry, these associations did not reach statistical significance. Among individuals of African ancestry, the OR was 1.33 (95% CI, 0.50-3.55; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .57), while among those of East Asian ancestry, the OR was 1.26 (95% CI, 0.66-2.41; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .48). Sensitivity analyses using the dIVW and MR-Median methods yielded consistent results overall (eTable 2 and eFigure 1 in <xref rid="note-ZOI241597-1-s" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplement 1</xref>).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="zoi241597t2" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2. </label><caption><title>Mendelian Randomization Estimates of Stress on Lung Cancer and by Histologic Subtypes, Across Ancestry</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><col width="29.62%" span="1"/><col width="13.22%" span="1"/><col width="16.7%" span="1"/><col width="26.24%" span="1"/><col width="14.22%" span="1"/><thead><tr><th rowspan="2" valign="top" align="left" scope="col" colspan="1">Outcome by ancestry</th><th colspan="2" valign="top" align="left" scope="colgroup" rowspan="1">No.</th><th rowspan="2" valign="top" align="left" scope="col" colspan="1">OR (95%CI)</th><th rowspan="2" valign="top" align="left" scope="col" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value<sup>a</sup></th></tr><tr><th valign="top" colspan="1" align="left" scope="colgroup" rowspan="1">Cases</th><th valign="top" align="left" scope="col" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Controls</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td valign="top" align="left" scope="col" rowspan="1" colspan="1">European</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Lung cancer</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">26 683</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">25 278</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.49 (1.13-1.98)</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.005</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Squamous cell carcinoma</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6107</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">23 173</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.69 (1.06-2.70)</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.03</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Adenocarcinoma</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2267</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">23 173</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.20 (0.81-1.79)</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.37</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Small cell lung cancer</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9791</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">23 173</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.73 (0.82-3.65)</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.15</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" scope="col" rowspan="1" colspan="1">East Asian</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Lung cancer</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7062</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5372</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.26 (0.66-2.41)</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.48</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Squamous cell carcinoma</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1292</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5372</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.58 (0.18-1.80)</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.34</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Adenocarcinoma</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4630</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5372</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.04 (1.00-4.18)</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.05</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Small cell lung cancer</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">99</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5372</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.04 (0.00-2.05)</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.11</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" scope="col" rowspan="1" colspan="1">African</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Lung cancer</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1987</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3774</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.33 (0.50-3.55)</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.57</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Squamous cell carcinoma</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">451</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3774</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.99 (0.53-17.00)</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.22</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Adenocarcinoma</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">844</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3774</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.58 (0.15-2.22)</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.43</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Small cell lung cancer</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">116</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3774</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.17 (0.04-31.45)</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">.93</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>Abbreviation: OR, odds ratio.</p><fn id="zoi241597t2n1"><label>
<sup>a</sup>
</label><p><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value estimates are based on Mendelian randomization with summary statistics by using Robust Adjusted Profile Score (ie, MR-RAPS).<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup></p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><fig position="float" id="zoi241597f1" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure. </label><caption><title>Summary of Results for Sensitivity to Environmental Stress and Adversity and Overall Lung Cancer Risk </title><p>Results from Mendelian randomization with summary statistics by using Robust Adjusted Profile Score analysis.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="jamanetwopen-e2457079-g001.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec id="H2-5-ZOI241597"><title>Association With Lung Cancer Risk by Histologic Subtype</title><p>We observed heterogeneity in the association between sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity and lung cancer risk across histologic subtypes among different population ancestries (<xref rid="zoi241597t2" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref> and eFigure 2 in <xref rid="note-ZOI241597-1-s" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplement 1</xref>). Among individuals of European ancestry, a significant association was noted among squamous cell carcinoma, with an OR of 1.69 (95% CI, 1.06-2.70; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .03) (<xref rid="zoi241597t2" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>). However, associations with adenocarcinoma and small cell lung cancer did not reach statistical significance. Among individuals of East Asian ancestry, sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity was associated with an increased risk of adenocarcinoma (OR, 2.04; 95% CI, 1.00-4.18; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .05). Notably, associations were not observed across any of the 3 histologic subtypes among individuals of African ancestry.</p></sec></sec><sec id="H1-4-ZOI241597"><title>Discussion</title><p>In this 2-sample MR analysis using GWAS summary data, we found a significant association of genetically estimated sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity in relation to lung cancer risk among individuals of European ancestry, as well as in a broader cross-ancestry analysis. Stress, as a physiological and psychological response to adverse conditions, is critically implicated in immune dysfunction that influence disease susceptibility.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref></sup> Prolonged exposure to stress is particularly concerning, as it can lead to enduring changes in emotional, physiological, and behavioral responses, thereby increasing individuals’ susceptibility to various health conditions.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>,<xref rid="zoi241597r19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref></sup> Those with increased sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity are likely exposed to chronic stress and hence heightened risk for worse health.</p><p>The association between stress and lung cancer is complex. Robust evidence suggests that stress can facilitate cancer progression by modulating key cancer hallmarks, as seen in animal studies and partially supported by clinical observations.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref></sup> A 2008 meta-analysis of 142 studies (mean sample size of 87 000) indicated that psychosocial stress estimates a modest increase in cancer incidence (HR, 1.06; 95% CI, 1.02-1.11; <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = .005), largely driven by depression.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref></sup> Studies on work stress as a cancer risk factor have yielded mixed results, with 1 meta-analysis<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref></sup> reporting null effects and another indicating elevated relative risks for lung and colorectal cancers.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref></sup> Despite the inconsistent effects observed in epidemiologic studies, animal studies suggest that stress can impact cancer progression by targeting stress-sensitive phases of tumor growth and metastasis.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref></sup> Unlike animal studies, epidemiologic studies and clinical trials on stress-reducing interventions typically do not focus on such stress-prone phases, which may explain the mixed results.</p><p>The current study revealed a significant association between sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity and an increased risk of lung cancer. Malignant development in humans is a prolonged process and subclinical cancer dormancy is common.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref></sup> Therefore, cancer risk may be elevated both through disease initiation and through escape from dormancy or accelerated progression to clinical manifestation. Animal studies have shown that stress factors can trigger tumor cells to escape dormancy.<sup><xref rid="zoi241597r24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref></sup> Further research is warranted to elucidate the underlying mechanisms driving the observed associations among humans. Moreover, our histologic subtype specific analysis showed heterogeneity across different population ancestries. The observed variations may reflect underlying genetic predisposition, environmental, and lifestyle differences, highlighting the complexity of lung cancer etiology. It also reflected the importance of considering both population diversity and histologic subtype when exploring lung cancer risk.</p><sec id="H2-6-ZOI241597"><title>Limitations</title><p>There are several limitations in the study. The genetic proxies were primarily associated with sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity, falling under the broader category of neuroticism—a psychological trait marked by a propensity toward emotions like guilt, embarrassment, and being easily hurt. Hence, these genetic markers may not fully capture the dynamic nature of sensitivity to all types of psychosocial stress. Additionally, the genetic instruments derived from populations of European ancestry. The relatively small sample sizes for individuals of African and East Asian ancestries constrained our statistical power, particularly in detecting associations across different histologic subtypes.</p></sec></sec><sec id="H1-5-ZOI241597"><title>Conclusions</title><p>In this genetic association study of 351 827 individuals from the UK Biobank and a cross-ancestry genome-wide analysis of 61 047 lung cancer cases and 947 237 controls, sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity were associated with lung cancer risk. Our findings suggest variability in this association across different lung cancer histologic subtypes and ancestries, pointing to the complex etiology and development of lung cancer. These results not only contribute to our understanding of lung cancer’s multifaceted nature but also underscore the necessity for further research into the nuanced association between psychosocial stress and cancer risk, with a particular focus on diverse populations.</p></sec></body><back><ref-list id="REF-ZOI241597"><title>References</title><ref id="zoi241597r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Nagel</surname>
<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Speed</surname>
<given-names>D</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>van der Sluis</surname>
<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Østergaard</surname>
<given-names>SD</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Genome-wide association study of the sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity neuroticism cluster</article-title>. <source>Acta Psychiatr Scand</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>141</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>476</fpage>-<lpage>478</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/acps.13155</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31972866</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kyrou</surname>
<given-names>I</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Tsigos</surname>
<given-names>C</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Stress hormones: physiological stress and regulation of metabolism</article-title>. <source>Curr Opin Pharmacol</source>. <year>2009</year>;<volume>9</volume>(<issue>6</issue>):<fpage>787</fpage>-<lpage>793</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.coph.2009.08.007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19758844</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Argentieri</surname>
<given-names>MA</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Nagarajan</surname>
<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Seddighzadeh</surname>
<given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Baccarelli</surname>
<given-names>AA</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Shields</surname>
<given-names>AE</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Epigenetic pathways in human disease: the impact of DNA methylation on stress-related pathogenesis and current challenges in biomarker development</article-title>. <source>EBioMedicine</source>. <year>2017</year>;<volume>18</volume>:<fpage>327</fpage>-<lpage>350</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2017.03.044</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28434943</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5405197</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Olvera Alvarez</surname>
<given-names>HA</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kubzansky</surname>
<given-names>LD</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Campen</surname>
<given-names>MJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Slavich</surname>
<given-names>GM</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Early life stress, air pollution, inflammation, and disease: an integrative review and immunologic model of social-environmental adversity and lifespan health</article-title>. <source>Neurosci Biobehav Rev</source>. <year>2018</year>;<volume>92</volume>:<fpage>226</fpage>-<lpage>242</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2018.06.002</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29874545</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6082389</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chida</surname>
<given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Hamer</surname>
<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Wardle</surname>
<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Steptoe</surname>
<given-names>A</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Do stress-related psychosocial factors contribute to cancer incidence and survival?</article-title>
<source>Nat Clin Pract Oncol</source>. <year>2008</year>;<volume>5</volume>(<issue>8</issue>):<fpage>466</fpage>-<lpage>475</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/ncponc1134</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18493231</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bray</surname>
<given-names>F</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Laversanne</surname>
<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sung</surname>
<given-names>H</given-names></string-name>, <etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Global cancer statistics 2022: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries</article-title>. <source>CA Cancer J Clin</source>. <year>2024</year>;<volume>74</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>229</fpage>-<lpage>263</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3322/caac.21834</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38572751</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Krewski</surname>
<given-names>D</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lubin</surname>
<given-names>JH</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Zielinski</surname>
<given-names>JM</given-names></string-name>, <etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Residential radon and risk of lung cancer: a combined analysis of 7 North American case-control studies</article-title>. <source>Epidemiology</source>. <year>2005</year>;<volume>16</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>137</fpage>-<lpage>145</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/01.ede.0000152522.80261.e3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15703527</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Malhotra</surname>
<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Malvezzi</surname>
<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Negri</surname>
<given-names>E</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>La Vecchia</surname>
<given-names>C</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Boffetta</surname>
<given-names>P</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Risk factors for lung cancer worldwide</article-title>. <source>Eur Respir J</source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>48</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>889</fpage>-<lpage>902</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1183/13993003.00359-2016</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27174888</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Shi</surname>
<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Shiraishi</surname>
<given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Choi</surname>
<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Genome-wide association study of lung adenocarcinoma in East Asia and comparison with a European population</article-title>. <source>Nat Commun</source>. <year>2023</year>;<volume>14</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>3043</fpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-38196-z</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37236969</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10220065</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Zuber</surname>
<given-names>V</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Grinberg</surname>
<given-names>NF</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Gill</surname>
<given-names>D</given-names></string-name>, <etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Combining evidence from Mendelian randomization and colocalization: review and comparison of approaches</article-title>. <source>Am J Hum Genet</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>109</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>767</fpage>-<lpage>782</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ajhg.2022.04.001</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35452592</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7612737</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Byun</surname>
<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Han</surname>
<given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname>
<given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Cross-ancestry genome-wide meta-analysis of 61 047 cases and 947 237 controls identifies new susceptibility loci contributing to lung cancer</article-title>. <source>Nat Genet</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>54</volume>(<issue>8</issue>):<fpage>1167</fpage>-<lpage>1177</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41588-022-01115-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35915169</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9373844</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r12"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Auton</surname>
<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Brooks</surname>
<given-names>LD</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Durbin</surname>
<given-names>RM</given-names></string-name>, <etal/>; <collab>1000 Genomes Project Consortium</collab></person-group>. <article-title>A global reference for human genetic variation</article-title>. <source>Nature</source>. <year>2015</year>;<volume>526</volume>(<issue>7571</issue>):<fpage>68</fpage>-<lpage>74</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nature15393</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26432245</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4750478</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r13"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Purcell</surname>
<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Neale</surname>
<given-names>B</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Todd-Brown</surname>
<given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <etal/></person-group>. <article-title>PLINK: a tool set for whole-genome association and population-based linkage analyses</article-title>. <source>Am J Hum Genet</source>. <year>2007</year>;<volume>81</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>559</fpage>-<lpage>575</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1086/519795</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17701901</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC1950838</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r14"><label>14</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Karlsson Linnér</surname>
<given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Biroli</surname>
<given-names>P</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kong</surname>
<given-names>E</given-names></string-name>, <etal/>; <collab>23and Me Research Team</collab>; <collab>eQTLgen Consortium</collab>; <collab>International Cannabis Consortium</collab>; <collab>Social Science Genetic Association Consortium</collab></person-group>. <article-title>Genome-wide association analyses of risk tolerance and risky behaviors in over 1 million individuals identify hundreds of loci and shared genetic influences</article-title>. <source>Nat Genet</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>51</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>245</fpage>-<lpage>257</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41588-018-0309-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30643258</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6713272</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r15"><label>15</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Zhao</surname>
<given-names>Q</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname>
<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Hemani</surname>
<given-names>G</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Bowden</surname>
<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Small</surname>
<given-names>DS</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Statistical inference in 2-sample summary-data Mendelian randomization using robust adjusted profile score</article-title>. <source>Annals of Statistics</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>48</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>1742</fpage>-<lpage>1769</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1214/19-AOS1866</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r16"><label>16</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Nagel</surname>
<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Speed</surname>
<given-names>D</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>van der Sluis</surname>
<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Østergaard</surname>
<given-names>SD</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Genome-wide association study of the sensitivity to environmental stress and adversity neuroticism cluster</article-title>. <source>Acta Psychiatr Scand</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>141</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>476</fpage>-<lpage>478</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/acps.13155</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31972866</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r17"><label>17</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Byun</surname>
<given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Han</surname>
<given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname>
<given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Cross-ancestry genome-wide meta-analysis of 61,047 cases and 947 237 controls identifies new susceptibility loci contributing to lung cancer</article-title>. <source>Nature Genetics</source>. <year>2022</year>;<volume>54</volume>(<issue>8</issue>):<fpage>1167</fpage>-<lpage>1177</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41588-022-01115-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35915169</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9373844</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r18"><label>18</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Cohen</surname>
<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Janicki-Deverts</surname>
<given-names>D</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Miller</surname>
<given-names>GE</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Psychological stress and disease</article-title>. <source>JAMA</source>. <year>2007</year>;<volume>298</volume>(<issue>14</issue>):<fpage>1685</fpage>-<lpage>1687</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/jama.298.14.1685</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17925521</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r19"><label>19</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Engert</surname>
<given-names>V</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Grant</surname>
<given-names>JA</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Strauss</surname>
<given-names>B</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Psychosocial factors in disease and treatment-a call for the biopsychosocial model</article-title>. <source>JAMA Psychiatry</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>77</volume>(<issue>10</issue>):<fpage>996</fpage>-<lpage>997</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2020.0364</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32492082</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r20"><label>20</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Eckerling</surname>
<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ricon-Becker</surname>
<given-names>I</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sorski</surname>
<given-names>L</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sandbank</surname>
<given-names>E</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ben-Eliyahu</surname>
<given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Stress and cancer: mechanisms, significance and future directions</article-title>. <source>Nat Rev Cancer</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>21</volume>(<issue>12</issue>):<fpage>767</fpage>-<lpage>785</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41568-021-00395-5</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34508247</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r21"><label>21</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Heikkilä</surname>
<given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Nyberg</surname>
<given-names>ST</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Theorell</surname>
<given-names>T</given-names></string-name>, <etal/>; <collab>IPD-Work Consortium</collab></person-group>. <article-title>Work stress and risk of cancer: meta-analysis of 5700 incident cancer events in 116,000 European men and women</article-title>. <source>BMJ</source>. <year>2013</year>;<volume>346</volume>:<fpage>f165</fpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bmj.f165</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23393080</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3567204</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r22"><label>22</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Yang</surname>
<given-names>T</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Qiao</surname>
<given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Xiang</surname>
<given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname>
<given-names>W</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Gan</surname>
<given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname>
<given-names>Y</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Work stress and the risk of cancer: a meta-analysis of observational studies</article-title>. <source>Int J Cancer</source>. <year>2019</year>;<volume>144</volume>(<issue>10</issue>):<fpage>2390</fpage>-<lpage>2400</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/ijc.31955</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30484859</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r23"><label>23</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Manjili</surname>
<given-names>MH</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Tumor dormancy and relapse: from a natural byproduct of evolution to a disease state</article-title>. <source>Cancer Res</source>. <year>2017</year>;<volume>77</volume>(<issue>10</issue>):<fpage>2564</fpage>-<lpage>2569</lpage>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-17-0068</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28507050</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5459601</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="zoi241597r24"><label>24</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><string-name name-style="western"><surname>Perego</surname>
<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Tyurin</surname>
<given-names>VA</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Tyurina</surname>
<given-names>YY</given-names></string-name>, <etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Reactivation of dormant tumor cells by modified lipids derived from stress-activated neutrophils</article-title>. <source>Sci Transl Med</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>12</volume>(<issue>572</issue>):<elocation-id>eabb5817</elocation-id>. doi:<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1126/scitranslmed.abb5817</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33268511</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8085740</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list><notes notes-type="supplementary-material" id="note-ZOI241597-1"><supplementary-material id="note-ZOI241597-1-s" position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><label>Supplement 1.</label><caption><p><bold>eTable 1. </bold>Single-Nucleotide Variants Included in Genetic Instruments</p><p><bold>eTable 2. </bold>Sensitivity Analysis of Mendelian Randomization Estimates of Stress on Lung Cancer and by Histologic Subtypes, Across Ancestry</p><p><bold>eFigure 1.</bold> Mendelian Randomization Estimates of Stress on Lung Cancer, by Histologic Subtypes, Across Ancestry</p><p><bold>eFigure 2.</bold> Meta-Analysis of Mendelian Randomization Estimates (MR_RAPS) of Stress on Lung Cancer by Histologic Subtypes, Across Ancestry</p></caption><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="jamanetwopen-e2457079-s001.pdf" position="float" orientation="portrait"/></supplementary-material><supplementary-material position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><label>Supplement 2.</label><caption><p>
Data Sharing Statement
</p></caption><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="jamanetwopen-e2457079-s002.pdf" position="float" orientation="portrait"/></supplementary-material></notes></back></article></pmc-articleset>